# **Kathryn Borne**

# **Summary**

Innovative and energetic Senior UX Designer and Senior Graphic Designer with over 15 years' experience creating exceptional visual designs and user-friendly experiences. Managing multiple projects simultaneously and meeting tight deadlines. Excellent communication skills and interpersonal skills, building positive relationships with internal and external customers.

# **Experience**

# Freelance & Contract Work - Graphic Designer and UX Designer/Developer

St. Petersburg, FL - January 2001- Present

- Create, develop, and update landing pages and websites, retaining new and existing prospects
- Design logos, brochures, social media ads and other marketing materials to boost customers' brands
- Enhance imagery and optimize photos for print and web to gain excitement of products and attract end users
- Produce motion graphic videos, music lyric videos and social media pieces to boost sales and engagement

# BenefitHub - UX Designer II

Tampa, FL - July 2015 - October 2024

- Created mockups for the BenefitHub employee discount platform to promote a compelling user experience
- Designed ADA compliant landing pages, web apps, widgets and more for ultimate user engagement
- Incorporated data-driven elements in mockups to accurately display various components of the platform
- Generated interactive prototypes with Adobe XD for user testing and optimizing design and functionality
- Developed responsive, mobile-first products using HTML5, CSS3, SASS and JavaScript to satisfy requirements
- Collaborated with team members and project managers via Slack, Jira and Zoom for effective communication
- Partnered with front-end and back-end developers for precision and on-time deliverables
- Inspected development projects with cross-browser testing across multiple devices for utmost accuracy
- Built Adobe Cloud libraries to replicate React.js components such as buttons, modals, form input fields, as well as style libraries for fonts and color themes to promote design consistency on all mockups

## Raymond James Financial - Web Admin Contractor

St. Petersburg, FL - February 2015 - June 2015

- Constructed websites with Sitecore CMS, HTML and CSS producing high conversion rates for financial officers, to increase their customer base
- Designed logos, graphics and web banners resulting in creative brand consistency throughout the site
- Edited, cropped and optimized photos using best practices increasing speed of delivery

## Sign-Age - Senior Graphic Designer and Web Assistant

Clearwater, FL - August 2011 - June 2014

- Updated the company website content and images using Firespring CMS to increase client engagement
- Designed various types of signs for retail, trade shows, vehicle wraps, wall murals, etc. ensuring customer satisfaction and repeat orders
- Prepared art files for wide-format printing and outsourcing to vendors resulting in ultimate print quality
- Produced 3D-sign technical drawings that assured city, county, and contract approvals needed for construction

# **Kathryn Borne**

# **Tampa Print Services** (now AlphaGraphics) - **Pre-Press Manager and Sr. Graphic Designer** Tampa, FL - April 2003 - March 2011

- Managed the pre-press dept., ensuring the press and digital depts. produced maximum quality products
- Handled design, pre-press and software updates to stay on schedule and ensure deadlines were met
- Designed logos, brochures, corporate identity packages, B2B materials and more for client engagement
- Prepared art files for offset, flexo, wide-format and digital printing for optimized printed materials

## **Education**

## St. Petersburg College

St. Petersburg, FL

Associate of Science - Computer Science, Web Development

# Coding Dojo Web Development Boot Camp

Mountain View, CA

Three-month web development training course

## Academy of Communicative Art and Design

Cincinnati, OH

Associate of Arts - Commercial Art and Design

#### Software

Adobe XD | Adobe Illustrator | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe InDesign | Adobe Audition | Adobe After Effects | Figma Microsoft Office Suite | Google Drive | Visual Studio | Visual Studio Code | Miro | Sitecore CMS | Firespring CMS

## **Skills & Tools**

Graphic Design | UI/UX Design | Front-End Development | Mobile-First Development | HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS JavaScript | jQuery | React.js | GitHub | Azure DevOps | Jira | Zoom | Slack | Cross-Browser Testing | Copywriting Technical Drawing | Technical Writing | Editing | ADA Compliance | Scrum | Agile